good morning welcome to our second live
solution raising number eight overall
and numbers day 17 of me going live at
8:30 in the morning every morning today
I'm joined by Eric and Edward and we are
having a solution raising on resiliency
efficiency and fragility which is a
conversation that was started in
thinking be space and Eric has a video
up about resiliency and efficiency I
believe or no it was really it was
efficiency and fragility it's two of the
three at any rate and say it's so yes it
was no I'll just say the same difference
with the two things he said same same
thing and so a solution raising is an
hour-long generative conversation at the
end we have solutions that we could
actually implement if we had 10,000
people and a hundred thousand dollars we
spend 15 minutes talking about what we
currently this space currently looks
like which under kovat 19 is a bit of a
it is actually a new exploration because
it's not the same old same old as every
time but we still give it 15 minutes 15
minutes to talk about a beautiful future
we would like to live into and then 30
minutes about an actual adjacent
possible what we could do a 10,000
people and $100,000 if we wanted to
right now without necessarily government
involvement or outside forces but beyond
those 10,000 so for each I will keep the
time for each section will send 15
minutes on the first one and anyone who
wants to start sharing Ken on what
resiliency efficiency and fragility look
like right now in our system should I
kick off just just as sort of as you
said they said just kick off and put it
in the context of the video kind of
things all right all right so yeah the
notion is that there is an inevitable
trade-off between resiliency and
efficiency right the more you optimize
for a particular function the more you
trim down on costs the more you trim the
fat the less able you are to respond to
the unexpected the other less redundancy
the less slack the less capacity
capacity there is to respond to the
unexpected and so that's that's the
essence of the argument so I gave a
couple of examples in the video of you
know staff training for example staff
being trained to do one particular
function in an organization rather than
a little bit of cross-training and you
know factories being optimized to make
one particular product as efficiently as
possible but to retool that Factory
becomes a big difficulty and so yeah in
the search for increasing profits and
increasing shareholder returns and
maximizing efficiency we have left
ourselves extremely exposed and fragile
to the impact of unexpected events and
so the only course of action when Co vid
hit was this massive overreaction in a
way right you know if shutting down the
entire economy because there was no
there was no other choice right there
were there was not the capacity to build
ventilators and test kits and erect a
spare Hospital capacity quickly enough
to avoid the necessity for widespread
lockdown so yeah that's that's basically
it the the inevitable trade-off that it
that always exists and acknowledging
that fact and building that into the
conversation right so when you are
designing a business when you are
designing a process having that has a
huge part of the design process to what
extent are we going to sacrifice
efficiently what additional costs are we
willing to bear for long-term resiliency
at what point does it get ridiculous
right it's doubling your annual costs to
be resilient to the future well your
business can survive under those
conditions right so there's a there's a
negotiation to be made between these two
things right but they do pull in
opposite directions and so it's a yes
and that there's no hard-and-fast set of
rules right is it needs to be an ongoing
conversation right I think I suppose
long enough sorry thank you Eric adora
do you want to share and then I can
share as well sorry yeah I definitely
agree with all that and it's really the
problem
as Eric pointed out it began this video
I believe one of the biggest problems
behind all this and we're looking
forward that we have to address one of
the things I'm interested in is is how
can we architect systems differently in
order to optimize between efficiency and
resiliency better so for example just an
example for for some things you know
instead of having you know to double the
cost or say you know have say you have a
factory and you have an assembly line
and suddenly you know for whatever
reason you have to you have to adapt
really quickly and switch over from
manufacturing cars to you know
ventilators for example you know having
all the parts on hand for all these
different scenarios is very expensive
and it's it's just a non-starter
basically but what if you design your
your systems initially in a more modular
way you know to think through things a
little better so that you don't have to
have so many parts on hand but you've
architected your whole assembly line in
such a way that it's more modular and
you can adapt faster so that that's just
one example of the kinds of things that
I'm thinking about thank you ever
it was weird cuz this before Cove in
nineteen this trade-off between
efficiency and something else to me was
about the industry is maximized for
their own individual profit which means
the industry is cost efficiency because
the pro end so thinking about this
before and making my notes I was like oh
what is that because what they've
maximized the efficiency of the process
so if they're making a cog they have
that down to the millisecond they have
it like the most profitable so they can
compete but the competition itself the
fact they all need their own mark
they all need their own their own sick
leave they all need all means that it
costs us for them to be in competition
with in the marketplace we don't get the
benefit of that efficiency but we get
the cost and so I have here that like
efficiency we've sacrificed efficiency
for profit in the name of like open 19
when there's an epidemic when there's a
catastrophe we don't know how to get
resiliency out of our current system and
yet even without that we because we've
maximized for efficiency in the name of
profit it's cost us our individual
resiliency as well as well as our system
resiliency and so how can we have both
how can we cuz right now our world of
business and entrepreneurship is
maximized for those who have a very high
risk threshold that is people who
whatever I'll figure it out when we get
there people like me who have a very low
risk threshold are like right no no I
need to have three months of supplies on
hand so I know that I know I can have
them for three months and I know that
that they're there that's not power
supply chain works it works that the
cogs were using on Tuesday come on
Monday the cogs are using next week come
next week and so in a catastrophe people
who are low risk and for who are high
who can handle high amounts of risk
aren't gonna be able to handle actual
high amounts of risk once it actually
hits the fan because they haven't dealt
with every contingency where's people
with a low risk tolerance who do think
of every contingency but but the market
can't allow you to put every contingency
in the place if you can deal with every
different pandemic that could happen
even just that even just because of
course this is a respiratory disease
that has a very specific thing in our
bodies that it that it showcases so we
need respirators we need masks a
different pandemic we need different
equipment you can't so maximizing for
this specific one to have resiliency and
this isn't gonna give you resiliency and
everything but it's just that that like
right now our our systems maximize for
those that need those that would be good
in this crisis aren't even in the
marketplace because they would've been
pushed out long ago in the competitive
marketplace you can't have all of that
resiliency be based on your business and
compete in the regular
place is what I'm trying to say so we
can now open it up for another five
minutes or so and then we can talk about
the beautiful future who can create
together that doesn't need to match but
I think I think an interesting thing to
explore might be the definition of
efficiency right because you you've kind
of brought that into question in what
you've just said Jubilee that actually
it's inefficient right the waste that
goes into multiple marketing campaigns
and you know doubling up on all kinds of
other processes is actually a giant cost
that society bears it's not it's not
efficient at all and also just adding to
that efficiency is about minimizing
costs and externalities right that's
that that's kind of what it's about and
so it's extremely anything and so but
you can't this has to be taken in a
long-term context right it may be
efficient 99 years out of a hundred to
cut the one-year and a hundred where
something hits you all of those gains
you made are more than lost right and so
efficiency needs to be measured not by
you know next quarter share prize not by
you know the bonuses we're going to get
this year and then what profits were
going to report and all of that kind of
thing efficiency needs to like the long
term metastability needs to be part of
the definition of efficiency do you see
what I mean that's that's kind of the
point I'm trying to make yeah that's a
really good point and I agree on the
metastability so efficiencies often you
know lead to externalities and and those
externalities you know don't work
towards metastability on the big level
so I think one one thing we need to
think about is how to internalize for
companies and individuals to internalize
more externalities in order to look at
the bigger metastable picture
yeah I have externalities underlying
here I think your your efficiency was
like cost and exponents and that is as a
when you're a business owner if you can
put off as many of those externalities
as you can for profit quite a profit is
some passed those externalities off onto
the population tragedy in the Commons I
don't care as long as I have this profit
and we don't account for those we don't
account for it's someone else that needs
to be recognized as inefficient right
that's that's the famine because it's
cutting my cost therefore you know
there's more efficient Meester that but
but actually yeah sorry I know that's
absolutely because that's I mean
capitalism our current economic system
if we actually included externalities
and we did this two decades ago we could
survive under capitalism because
capitalism would the price point would
tell you whether something is actually
environmentally friendly socially just
all these things would be included in
the price but we haven't done that up to
this point and then you if you included
the externalities in your cost you
couldn't compete in the marketplace
whereas it has to be industry-wide it
has to be everybody includes their
extremities we have to include the extra
knowledge even just the knowledge of the
externalities is um something that could
be be used to know that yes your flight
cost 300 but it actually cost the world
3,000 so you just passed off 2700 onto
everybody else even just knowing that
make some people deterred from from
using its they don't feel like they're
passing off not everyone and we needed
it to be everyone we need the cost of
the ticket if it cost 3,000 to be 3,000
and then people who can't afford it
maybe we subsidize in other ways but not
we need the price to be there if we're
using a pricing system if we're using
this I think it's too late for that and
we need something new but we could have
that good stuff right um using kind of a
Daniels mocking burger analogy here
imagine you know the body and if each
cell was optimizing for itself and you
know if you look at on the level of the
body each if each cell was maximizing
efficiency first so
externalizing everything else from the
perspective of the body as a whole it
becomes very inefficient if you've you
you know all your externalities move
outwards and the inefficiency of the
body of the hole increases as each cell
maximizes its own efficiency yeah this
is exactly the problem with money right
is that it does it what it is incapable
of measuring value in a whole range of
domains right you know that the forest
which is standing there is that worth
more chopped down and turn into lumber
or is it worth more to forest with all
the birds and the insects and the bla
bla bla bla bla that live there right
and you can't put a monetary value on
value B right I mean there's undeniably
a value there but you can't and so when
when numbers is your measuring system
it's always the right thing to do to
chop that forest down right it's worth
more dollar when you drop it down than
it is if you leave it there and so it's
always the right call to chop it down
though yeah they're the whole measuring
system needs to change that will that
the value system needs to expand beyond
just numbers I mean numbers have their
place obviously there's certain measures
in numbers right but yeah they're they
they they are but one tool they use to
stay in their place and not go
everywhere else well it's it's like yeah
numbers definitely have their place and
you know it's it's how we abstract the
metrics down to simple metrics you know
it's like IQ you know I'm gonna take a
whole complex yeah you know it's like I
mean thinking about it as a projection
of my body as a shadow on the sidewalk
you know the amount of information
that's lost in the shadow compared to
the rich information about my action
what I what and who I am you know it's
it's that loss of information
to a point making heuristics which
simplify complex things so that you
don't have to run through the
calculation every single time you know
what I mean making here is very useful
and it makes life you know it makes life
much more livable than it would
otherwise be the problem comes when your
heuristic oversimplifies the actuality
to the degree where it no longer of any
use whatsoever as a guide right and I
use an excellent example of that I think
I mean it is all but meaningless right
in terms of measuring someone's actual
ability and capacity to live and act in
the world right it's it's all but
meaningless but you shine enough
attention on it and tell people it's
meaningful and all of a sudden people
rely on it for all kinds of stupid
right you know it's it's like all these
things have usefulness and utility but
it's almost like we don't have the
wisdom to know when the tool is
applicable and when it yeah we're the
band yep yeah like bureaucracies like me
it's the map to follow so we don't need
to have all of this inconsistency but
then it it you're not doing on a
case-by-case basis and bureaucracy
people always fall through the cracks
systems always fall the cracks you find
a way to game it or lose by it and it's
not actually there but we're at the
15-minute mark so you can move on to the
next one I'm just gonna ask Edward when
you're not talking to mute because
there's like a clicking sound that's
that case Aaron I was gonna say normally
it's because I talked to Eric so often
that it's not I don't think it's coming
from his end but look at me making
assumptions that are absolutely wrong so
the next part we're talking about our
our individual version of an ideal
future in this in this space so for
resiliency efficiency and fragility what
could it look like 5 10 100 years down
the road however much time we need that
to be in order for us to feel like it's
a possibility for this world to exist
and our worlds don't need to match we
don't need to democratically vote on
which one we're voting for just what is
your ideal version of a future in that
most been roughly 13 minutes talking
about that
so pepper I'd like to start or I can
research I guess for me it's something
along the lines I mean as we've already
said right recognizing the reality of
this
trade-off that it is a thing right and
it needs to be from the center equally
recognizing the certainty that
unexpected events are going to come
along and give us a kick up the ass from
time to time right I mean we may not be
able to predict exactly what it is or
when it's going to come but we know for
certain that they are coming right and
so you know sticking your head in the
sand and hoping that it's not going to
happen is not a useful strategy so yeah
the I I would like in the Fiona this is
this is a sort of ongoing thing as far
as I'm concerned but I would just like
that to be from now on always part of
the process of design right whenever
you're designing anything be it a
product be it a system be a a community
whatever it is that you know the the the
the optimizing for a lightweight edward
said before he phrased it really nicely
optimizing for the correct balance
between resiliency and efficiency right
rather than optimizing for one or the
other attempting to of it and listen
that's easier said than done right I
mean it's not there's no there's no easy
lines to be drawn here that are always
going to work it's an ongoing
conversation that needs to be had and so
but yeah I would like to see it on a
sort of fractal kind of arrangement
right where it where resiliency is built
into the system at every single level
where every individual holds say a month
worth of supplies in the house and so
that you know they don't need to panic
on day one when when when something
comes along unexpected they don't need
to panic for a little while they can
stop breathe get their bearings figure
out what the best course of action is
you don't mean without without being
under too much stress and and so on and
so on right that you know each block in
a neighborhood has a generator and and
you know a big tank of water or
something like that you know this kind
of thing you can you can distribute
resilience at all kinds of levels and
yeah I mean one one that I mentioned in
the video which I mean I think this is
why Edwards here because he really liked
this idea was using the reserve idea
like they do with the military having
you know reserves you do a couple of
weeks a year training with the full-time
military so that they can be usefully
supportive when the time comes and you
could do the same in all kinds of
domains of essential services you know
in food production and
Logistics and delivery and maintaining
of power grids and water purification
systems and all of this kind of thing
I'm you could have tens of thousands
hundreds of thousands of reserves in the
nation always available at the drop of a
hat to you know come and offer support
should something go out so yeah that's
that's that's what I that's broadly what
I would like to see for the future is a
fractal at every level resilience being
built in in the most efficient way right
building resilience in in the most
efficient way that you can
thanks Eric conical head hurt
hold on I'm there yeah I really like the
reserved idea I mean it really builds
capacity and probably more dimensions
and I'm thinking of that in two ways one
when if you have that capacity of of
people that are cycling through and and
so you can ramp up your capacity when
you need it like the military does with
the reserves but another function that
serves is that you have all these human
beings playing the role of reserves and
they're all still learning something
about about something they wouldn't
learn otherwise that's the kind of
capacity that's gonna propagate into the
society as a whole in a completely
different way um and and I think that is
is extremely valuable all right I agree
my vision of the future for resiliency
efficiency and fragility is that we
definitely if we have a pricing system
that we definitely include externalities
within those prices that every industry
because we have access to the
information in the data and we are the
ones who actually have the power as to
who means in business by who we support
with our dollar having the max amount of
transparency for how resilient is your
system where is your profit coming from
where is your money going how how can we
help you be resilient having contingency
plans in place for every scenario
doesn't necessarily mean implementing
those plans but knowing what what do we
need to have on hand this is this is
happening let's since execute plan Q
because there's this you know a
respiratory condemn ik I mean the people
who do have the low risk tolerance
people with high anxiety who thought see
every scenario I need it to be in place
having those people working through the
game of pandemic hit what do we do now
and having a system so that it doesn't
matter if you're someone who puts your
head in the sand we aren't going to so
we're gonna know that your business is
fragile with transparency and we're
gonna have contingency and planner
why are you to have a contingency plan
for all of for all of these things
because we don't know what the next
thing is right is it an earthquake is it
a famine is it a pandemic is it a war
and so knowing having that resiliency
every level because even it doesn't
actually matter how set you are for the
for the resiliency if your community
isn't if your surrounding area isn't if
it isn't enough food if there isn't
enough electricity then you're then it's
a truly scarce resource and you're gonna
be fighting to the death for it as
opposed to hey let's let the ostrich you
don't what about their head in this and
let's prepare for them as well without
it needing to be everyone has their of
three months worth of supplies if you
have a three months worth of supply and
none of your neighbors do it's no longer
three months worth of supply it's a two
days worth of supply for your
neighborhood because you yeah I mean I
didn't want to live through that world
of my neighbors starving and and I have
enough food that I've decided to live
for three months instead of all this
living for a week and so making sure
that we do have the externalities
involved the data is is available and we
have created a system where we feel
comfortable putting our information in
there's a lot of ways that data can be
used in any type of situation that I can
see how it would work in the pandemic
and yet no one is gonna sign up for it
because Google and the government's
doing it it's catastrophic and horrible
whereas us being able to do it us being
able to track our equate our connections
right so that if we know if we get Kovan
19:00 they can tell everyone we've been
in contact with i don't want that sister
to be in place at google in the
government are the ones doing it i know
after all nefarious purposes they could
put that too but if we created that so
that we could protect ourselves and we
made it safe and we weren't going to
share it with the government then it's a
different a different system and so
having the ability to access
corporations and government data that's
already there been in a usable way as
well as feeling safe and comfortable to
put our information into a system that
would most benefit us and the collective
is what i would like to see for the
future we have five more minutes open it
up and talk about think okay I guess
related to what you were just saying
Julie Jordan or
all wrote an article for medium a short
while ago in which he proposed that
organizations such as Facebook and
Google should be in fiduciary
relationship with their users right
given that there is without question a
massive power asymmetry between the user
and the host service right and so in I
know you understand its but just for
anyone that else is watching this that
because you know in the same way that
your lawyer or your accountant or your
psychiatrist you know they know a great
deal more about you than you do about
them and could potentially use that to
their advantage at your expense right
and so they are legally obliged to use
what they know about you only in your
best interests right that that is the
relationship they must use the
information they have only in your
interest and it seems clear to me
obvious to me that Facebook and Google
fall into this category as well and so
if that was to change if their role in
society was to change from commercial
money-making venture get the sticky as
you can people keep people on site for
as long as you can to maximize your
advertising revenue if that was no
longer their model but instead they were
essentially a public utility right and
that they were absolutely in service to
each and every user on that database
right and had a fiduciary responsibility
to use what they know about them to use
their data only to support them in their
wishes right that that is now a
situation in which we could give our
data to them and that could be used in a
way that could ameliorate a lot of the
effects of sudden unexpected large
shocks because as you quite rightly say
I mean particularly with a pandemic
there the the contact tracing capability
of everybody being plugged into this
thing and you know knowing exactly where
everyone's been and who they've come
into contact with yeah it's a nightmare
in terms of big brother-type thing but
it's unbelievably useful tool to target
testing and vaccinations and so on when
there's a limited supply of them so yeah
it's you know things like that begin
with a redefining of cuz I don't listen
III know you want to build
thing by among us which we own and
therefore we all participate in and
therefore we can trust I get that
however right now what there is is
Facebook and Google right and so if they
could be repurposed to become that then
that is a much more immediate solution
right yeah and you're right I wasn't
like no I don't want base buckin but
this is the payments already in place
and I see like there's things I agree to
and things I don't agree - I agree that
I would want my data to be used for the
greater good for tracing contacts I in
no way want my daughter to be used for
for vaccinations because I don't believe
in forced vaccination I believe in in
any medical thing that you do should be
pro and con with you and your doctor you
decide if it's worth it for you and then
is that better for the collective
benefit however I definitely see forced
vaccination especially in this one
coming down the line and so the first
step of collecting our data for Facebook
is that then we have the you know it's
like well all your contacts are gonna
know if you know if you choose not to
vaccinate well did are they privy to me
and my doctors conversation like who
will like because if they're not then
they don't understand why we chose that
if we are Pete it like it's just there's
a lot of room for issues when it's
Facebook and I'm realizing now that I'm
arguing your idea of the future which is
not supposed to be a Facebook has
beautiful intentions and they do nothing
but good things with our data because
you know the thing that we're talking
about then you know it's it's like a
ready-made solution you don't need to
build a new one from scratch and you
know and it is it's a conversation of
what would make us feel safe enough to
give back down at at Facebook and
honestly it's Facebook isn't Facebook
it's not yes that's correct ice book is
no longer face because we understand it
yet yeah well I think expanding the
whole fiduciary responsibility thing
even further would address part of the
forced vaccination problem because what
one reason people don't want to be
forced to have vaccinations is that a
lot of people believe that the process
the whole
nation process is not transparent to
begin with so if there's a fiduciary
responsibility of the people creating
researching and producing vaccinations
as well you know then then that helps
mitigate that problem as well so that
the whole idea of a forced vaccination
just kind of goes away
at that point yeah I mean that's the
issue if it's either kind of open
transparency or closed transparency if
everything's open transparency and the
finances and the science is open then
and we truly can see are these vaccines
safe and effective because we are we are
part of that system this is the best we
have we're gonna see if they're safe and
effective one of my issues with
vaccination is there's been no long-term
Studies on them so the short-term
studies absolutely big risk ratio reward
you should get vaccinated but the
decades-long studies have never been
done autoimmune stud nothing has been
done on it long term and yet I would
feel safer if they were like right we
don't know that yet
we can't know that because we haven't
started it we're starting it so ten
years twenty years thirty years down the
road we'll have better information but
the best thing we can do right now is
vaccinate I understand why we don't do
that because that sounds to the
layperson ooh that sounds like grey
science and I want black and white
science or not and it's like all science
is gray that is science
we never know the truth unless we're
seeking it and I want to know we're
seeking the truth and so have enough
access information because we thought we
grow in the truth before right I mean
with all the best intentions thought we
know the truth we need to discover later
on completely wrong and you know this is
this is the nature of science there is
always that not even just the chance for
likelihood that what you think right now
actually is at the very best incomplete
and very possibly completely wrong yeah
you know that's that's the nature of the
beast as you say yeah okay we are at the
30 minute mark
past it so we can go on to the the third
and final part of the solution racing
which is talking about what we could
if we had 10,000 people and $100,000
this is generally a solution that's not
coercive or requires our governments and
it only requires the ten thousands
people to be involved in it but we'll
see where it goes because it is Kovac 19
and it's hard to do anything with like
resiliency if it's not but what could we
do with ten thousand people and a
hundred thousand dollars to maximize our
resiliency and efficiency and minimize
our fragility well I think if you're
gonna impose that boundary on it the the
ten thousand people sort of boundary on
it then you are because I as as you
absolutely rightly said Jubilee there's
no point you being resilient if nobody
around you is resilient right because it
just erodes your resilience and so yeah
if you if you're gonna do it on if we're
talking that kind of scale then I do
think it's you know small town or
section of a city or something like that
where you know the 10,000 people in that
locality in geographic proximity to each
other come up with a plan everybody puts
in ten dollars and they come up with a
plan where they're gonna spend their
hundred thousand dollars on building
resiliency within that within that
community of 10,000 people right and so
and again there's gonna be a range of
solutions at that scale from individuals
stocking up with you know cans and you
know spending ten dollars a month for a
year for example stocking up with canned
food and frozen food so they've got at
least a month's worth of supplies in the
house you know forty for example maybe
that hundred thousand dollars is spent
on I don't know half a dozen diesel
generators so people can plug into them
if the power goes out or a water tower
right so you've always got you know
fifty thousand gallons of fresh water on
hand should the should the water supply
become contaminated or unusable for
whatever reason so yeah these these
sorts of solutions are sort of within
budget I think at that kind of scale
especially if you're talking ten
thousand people contributing ten dollars
a month on a monthly basis ongoing right
then you can really over the space of a
year or two you could really build some
significant resilience into that
community but the the reserves thing
doesn't doesn't really work at that
scale I mean that really does need to be
a
at a national kind of scale I think
because you know you're mobilizing
national capacity when it's necessary so
yeah it's up to you whether or not you
want to expand beyond the ten ten
thousand hundred thousand well for that
I mean I that is a bigger version of
what we were talking about before if I'm
set but my neighbors aren't they're
gonna come and steal my stuff if the ten
thousand people are set but the
surrounding communities are involved
yeah and they can still come in and
taste so it becomes part of the seizure
but I mean ten thousand people there's
other things that we can do to maximize
or have that trade off the trade off be
efficient right the trade off be
maximized rather than one or the other
be baptised and to me mapping our supply
chain right just knowing where things
come from and where things go having a
platform of for ten thousand people who
are Preppers ten thousand people who
love thinking about contingency plans
and are like hey this time that make
this pandemic or this earthquake like is
Vancouver set for this and having them
having a contingency plan set out for
all of these different things that
doesn't rely on our governments to do it
in fact it's like hey here's what we've
already come up with when when something
heads isn't necessarily making sure
because we don't have the power we can't
make sure it's it's in force but we
could offer it right hey under an
earthquake here's what we do under this
kind of pandemic or having what you just
said of the individual community of
10,000 right how do we feed us how do we
walk how do we water us how do we make
sure that we have our supplies that
could be something that the research is
done on on a worldwide level right what
does it take to do that for a small town
in BC what does it take what is the best
source of water or what is the best
source of electricity what is the best
way to grow food and when do we need to
start right like are we gonna be food
scarce and so Mads those were a bunch of
different options we clearly couldn't do
all of that for a hundred thousand
dollars what we could do possibly one of
them right and say like what is mapping
our supply chain to just know where's
the stuff I'm buying coming from and
knowing okay well you know my box of
zero maybe comes from Detroit
but where did their ingredients come
from to be able to make it and to be
able to map that to the best of our
ability especially the 10,000 people
were coders and statisticians that
wanted to contribute to a project like
this and with that there could be a
voluntary reserve system of hey under a
pandemic we need medical personnel
trains we want to have a hundred
thousand in Canada are you willing it
takes two weeks out of your life every
year right and so there might be enough
people who volunteer but it doesn't need
to be top-down right it doesn't need to
be hey we have a new Army Reserve
everyone has to go into something that
could just be hey we needed to know we
have enough people to stand behind
beside people and put IVs in and test
them if there's a pandemic or enough
people who know how to dig people out in
an earthquake or enough people know how
to scrape oil off a duck in an oil spill
right like that these are the skills we
need or we just need a person knows
those skills and now we can quickly
train other people
what is our contingency plan in all of
these things how can we have a rapid
response it occurs through this could
also this Reserve's notion could also be
done at a more local level right you
don't you don't actually have to rely on
government to do that and so in those
10,000 communities you know you could
have a sort of generalized blueprint
where these are the essential skills
that are likely to be needed in case of
emergency in a sort of broad general
sense right and so within your ten
thousand you know part of your emergency
response plan is to make sure that you
have electricians and plumbers and
builders and truck drivers and whatever
I mean I'm struggling to come up with a
long list of examples off the top of my
head but you get the point
right and so even at that relatively
localized level you could yeah you could
you know yeah mate who's a plumber and
so he goes and spends a couple of weeks
a year being a plumber with his mate and
learns the basics of it you know that
that kind of thing seems reasonable
yeah and having a map of that who are
the plumbers in our in our in our
neighborhood and who if there's like
right now essential circus or essential
workers or grocery store clerks and I've
been a grocery store clerk it does take
some training but not a lot of training
there I guarantee you there are a ton of
people who aren't immune-compromised
who'd be willing to step into that
position especially in a pandemic even
if they wouldn't normally be willing to
do that job because it's seen as an
essential service because they feel like
they're doing good they would be willing
to step into that role we don't have
that system in place right it's up to
save on foods to hire someone to come
and do that which means they have to go
through their whole process during that
instead of like hey who's not even
compromised who has these qualities who
can put things through and run a bag and
we don't need you to be fast and
efficient like we normally do when
you're when you're a grocery store clerk
because this is not the time for that
right it's about not passing on the
virus not knowing all the codes for all
the produce well yeah you know I think I
think there's a lot of small communities
where you know everybody pretty much has
a sense of what everybody's skills are
um you know they don't have to go out
and hire somebody from somewhere else
everybody but the the problem with a
small community embedded in our global
community is there's not enough skill
sets to handle like a lot of things that
are you know more globally oriented like
you know you might have a community with
a lot of plumbers and electricians
everybody's covered on that level but is
there any person who has the IT skills
to deal with an internet you know outage
or something like that so you know
conversely in urban areas like where I
live you don't know what skills their
neighbors have for the most part you
don't really even know them so you know
to have some way of surfacing that
information who knows what you know who
has what capacities you know so both of
those dynamics on the rural skin level
and on the urban ya know I like
something else
left most most of the certainly the
existing problem of lack of resilience
is what's the word I'm looking for I
can't think of the right word but it's a
it's a bigger problem in urban
environments and it is in rural
environment all environments are already
to some extent resilient in the sense
that they don't go shopping as often and
so they have more in the house right you
know they've got generators because they
live miles away and the power goes out
from time to time and so this you know
this resilience is already kind of in
the culture in in rural environments to
a far greater extent than it is in urban
in urban people who live in cities and
have lived in cities their whole lives
are the ones who really need to learn a
little bit of basic self-reliance kind
of and and also mindset right when
you're so used to having everything
we've got to do is pop out to the shops
and you can have win it whatever you
want if that goes away you've got you've
got you've got nothing and there are
like a set number of skills that are
absolutely essential and everybody
should have one of them because then
together we have all of them but having
a backup option that is even potentially
better than a individual expert is
having and one of them we could do with
ten thousand people one hundred thousand
dollars is to figure out what those
systems are like we could create we did
this solution racing on food we could
create a food app that helps you garden
and coordinate with your neighbors with
hundred thousand dollars so that it
didn't matter what your skill was it
just matters do you have a plot of land
and we want like it'll help you
literally like automate that process as
much as possible having the ability
where right now like if my kid gets hurt
and I would normally take her to the ER
I might be less likely to take her to
the ER is there a first aid app right
that is like hey hey what do I do in
this situation when is it when is the
threshold for risk to go to the ER the
same as as it was before right do I go
for chest pains now or do I not because
before I would always have to go and I'm
like I always have chest pains it's not
a it's not a metric
don't want to get but having like
especially if you don't have access to
doctors but you have access to a phone
anywhere in the world if it's like well
what do we do with this that would be
very helpful and yet there's legal
reasons you can't necessarily do that in
Canada in the United States right well
you're not a doctor you can't write but
is this better than no doctor right is
this better than no food and there can
be systems that we put in place to give
you some of that expertise and then we
need the contingency plan for what
happens when electricity and internet
goes out when we don't have access to
but it is the possibility of Acts access
to an expert and connect experts right
that we could have your agricultural
expert be connected to an agricultural
next expert all over the world and
they're talking about how do we how do
we create this resiliency in every
neighborhood how do we make sure that
there's enough food that's appropriate
for our community and our people we
let's do this that's right we only lost
this picture I'm sure he'll be back well
listening this is also an excellent
communication network in science of
emergency right and so the nurses and
doctors who live in your little 10,000
unit right they are in communication
with doctors and nurses in lots and lots
and lots of other units and so they are
also a valuable information resource to
you know what's going on what should be
what what should and shouldn't we be
worried about you know what's going on
in other places but you heard this kind
of thing and it's is straight from the
coalface kind of thing you know what I
mean it's not being processed through
media outlets it's it's it's ya know I
like it I like it and figuring that out
I mean it'd be great but if that was
already in place for hospitals to say
right we're quiet our our doctors and
nurses are literally sitting here every
shift board
oh you're overrun and you're only five
kilometres away right like how do we
knew now how do we keep the nurses
stapled
don't get why they don't just run some
ambulances with patients from one to the
other I mean what the how hard is
that to do I can't well some of it is
you want coal bid nineteen hospitals and
non-coated nineteen hospitals if you
have reasonable Hospital density you can
do that absolutely I've been with a ICU
doctor who's saying that normally every
day on average he would get
approximately one referral for sepsis
coming to him right and that in the last
two weeks three weeks he had not had one
single referral for sepsis come his way
where are these patients he was asking
where the are they they're not
going to other doctors you know I mean
that's my job that's what I do
so what's happening to them and so the
worry is that people are being shunted
out of emergency rooms too quickly or
are staying at home and not going to the
hospital at all for fear of being a
burden on the healthcare system or of
catching Kovac 19
it's a worry sorry my kid was being loud
I don't deal with that but let's get
back to the topic so I missed whether we
were actually back on topic but like
what we could do now for resiliency and
efficiency with 10,000 people $100,000
it's loud but sorry I dropped out there
for a few minutes I had a call come in
take care of um yeah so I like the idea
of well there's the advantage of a whole
community because a lot of these
resilience ease and fragilities are you
know that if you separate them out they
you need to look at it as a full-stack
you know you have because they're all
related to each other in some way so the
the advantage of doing it with a small
community where you can where you can
address a lot more the fragilities and
resilience ease and optimizations would
be advantageous but the question is I
mean say say you determine for a certain
community okay we we've got this
community pretty resilient now that we
think it can withstand a lot of
different kinds of shocks question is
because you've done it on a small scale
does that scale you know so so there's
the advantage then of doing it the other
way where you look at something like
just reserves on a larger scale and you
put your resources your 10,000 people
and your $100,000 towards that on a much
larger scale maybe just to bootstrap it
or something
so there's advantages obviously to that
because then you know at least in that
one domain that you know it will work I
think I mean sir here I think I sorry I
just saying I think you need both that
was really all I wanted to say but I
really do think you need both as Jubilee
was saying before right if if this scale
is okay but this scale isn't well
you know this scale soon breaks down at
that scale and so yeah it does it does
need to be across all scales otherwise
you you've created fragility at the
weakest point you know what I mean yeah
and that is I mean we're connected we
are globally connected and if we're not
looking after everyone we're not really
looking after anyone and so unless as
you can you can be as resilient as you
can yourself but that's clearly gonna
help it's gonna kind of help to be rural
and have the generators the most fragile
point right yes right well that's that's
part of the debate right now about you
know as far as top-down or localism as
far as dealing with the pandemic it's
like some some local areas have done it
very well but you know they're connected
to everybody else too so if they've done
it really well and their neighbor hasn't
you know you can't ignore that because
basically now you're into the weakest
link of the chain type of thing yeah
yeah I mean I think there's a lot we
could do with 10,000 people we had
10,000 people who are like hey I want to
be most helpful during this pandemic or
the next one or the next one and we did
have we had a list of five or six
professions that word that we could use
resiliency in that we could use those
reserves in medical professionals so
clearly we're not going to train you to
be a nurse in in two weeks but we can
train you to put an IV and we can train
you to do whatever the next essential
thing is for this particular one how do
you know it do me have garbage
collectors do you have like what are the
factional essentials and then do you
want to have other youtube videos yeah I
can think I can think of a few and yeah
absolutely and it's it's not as you say
to be cut to get them experts as it but
you know you you know in a hospital for
example people contempt e bedpans they
can change sheets they can clean floors
they can move beds around you know I
mean it's all kinds of really useful
stuff they can do that requires a
minimum of training and I'm sure that's
true in all kinds of domains must be
yeah and so we could like 10,000 people
getting together saying where do you
need us most and how do i how do i train
my
I get most trained and most useful
within that and having people in those
areas right people in hospitals and
saying yes we could use volunteers to do
X Y & Z right and and how do we then get
those people the supplies they need if
it's let's say making masks how do we
get them the supplies they can make
masks the fastest or how do we employ
the people who want to be employed
hopefully on a volunteer basis
most efficiently and knowing that they
want to knowing where they're needed and
then training them for it especially if
it was as easy as YouTube videos right
it was like hey here are the mechanical
ones you need you're not gonna be a
mechanic at the end of this but you're
gonna know how you know the basics
there's a spot where you can change an
oil field so yeah absolutely that's yeah
that's that's a really good solution I
think because basically what you're
doing is you're taking the low-hanging
fruit as far as skills come the
low-hanging fruit across a wide range of
domains and scales and that and that's
that's yeah it's the you know 80% of the
benefit for 20% of the work and that's
enough right that's that's enough that's
always enough yeah if you can ever do
that that's everybody they're pretty
good it's getting that other that other
20% with 80% of the work that you want
to let go that's when you're getting
into your investing too much in
resilience right and your you're
sacrificing too much in the way of
efficiency so yeah that sweet spot that
8020 sweet spot feels about about right
to me you know what I mean that feels
about the kind of level that we should
be that we should be aiming at
I mean I do find this particular thing
that happened Cove in nineteen the
community that I would have thought was
the most set up for antifragility is my
co-hosting community and yet they're
actually anti optimized for this like
I'm doing a better job this far out
because I my kids aren't used to running
in and out of each other's houses right
my kid they're not used to eating at
each other's houses and touching
everything and they're not as close to
the community they don't share a common
huh
a common house so in every other
contingency they would have been better
off but not a communicable disease that
you can't see for two weeks
like even explains me why in a community
like that why people can't mix with each
other within the community to me there's
four nurses who live there they're not
isolated and then what their kids have
to stay inside but everyone else gets to
run it like the thing is we're not
insulated communities and that's part of
when this hit this is the whole point of
communities why is that is there in
times like this at least you know at
least you've got that and so yeah it
seems to be no point living living in
the community if in times like this you
can't lean on your community right
what's the point they are there
absolutely like in other ways they're
set up like they don't have to pop out
to the grocery store they have a
spreadsheet they're communicating
they're figuring it out but they they're
their life is more drastically impacted
by this they can't use the playroom they
can't use things that they normally
would their not having cohousing dinners
they're not doing a lot of the things
they normally would understand it way a
lot of us as anyone that is anyone
that's a nice people and there's nurses
like this is the isolation for two weeks
and no one's sick then they can start
mixing within that community
they're never gonna sell fight like this
is the problem with all of our society
that there are people who are self
isolating but but not really because you
have to go to the grocery store your
groceries have to come to you so that
could always have it on you can always
be single but especially when there's
four people who are nurses and doctors
and they go oh right they go to their
profession and they come home there and
they're kids if they're if their kids
need to be looked after because they're
in an essential service they have to go
to a center or even a small small place
so they're they're still vector points
and they're hi vector points right
nurses and doctors go into the hospital
where the sick people are and then
coming home and their kids going to play
with other kids is not insulated room
unity and your nurse with only senior
people then yeah you
interspersed in fact you should that's
why having a smaller Dunbar community
the people quarantine when they come
into is kind of the best way to deal
with a pandemic but it's not doable in
Vancouver right because that's because
we all have individual lives and it's
not designed for it to be different than
that like right when this hit we every
there should be in all the office
buildings all the things that could be
converted to apartments or RDR
apartments but they're empty should be
hospital like move people out for
doctors and nurses absolutely so they
don't have to go mixing with their
community absolutely absolutely and they
can take their kids with them and it's
pleasant and nice accommodation yeah
absolutely I was just thinking exactly
that why not isolate them again amongst
themselves right so they can mix with
each other but they can't mix with the
outside world and since that's Izmir
much better way to go about isolation is
to draw boundaries around right you guys
stay within this thing right if anyone
gets sick they stay isolated within that
isolate you know within that zone but at
least no but the but at least then
you've got some kind of I mean that
seems me to be just as effective it
really would you know if there is an
outbreak it's contained to this 50
people 100 people or whatever I remember
there was this TV show I think it was a
few years ago and it was about a like
horrible disease and it like kills you
within 24 hours and you get it what it
and I didn't because they sectioned off
and and these people had to deal with it
themselves and they were starving and
there was chaos and there was I was like
wait if it's 2 days why aren't you just
like letting people who aren't sick
going to a bigger one and then like you
could solve this in a week like I don't
understand because but it's this one
that takes two weeks to incubate I'm
like just let them out to a bigger
quarantine if they're not sick and then
keep the sick people inside and then
eventually that circle gets bigger and
bigger where you know they're not sick
and you can let them out but anyway I
don't know what they on topic or you're
talking about like they're smarter ways
to do things exactly the same idea just
you know slightly slightly different
shape to it but exactly the same idea no
I don't get it I don't get it there's
guys
this well it's like the will of that
right that the governments would have to
say hey where do we have like they don't
own the office tower they don't own the
building so they have to co-opt it or
they have to say hey all of the people
who aren't verses and doctors need to
move out of this building because nurses
and doctors are moving into this
building because this is how we need to
deal with this it's better if it's empty
right it's better if it's one that was
just built so no one's going in it's
like sorry you're not moving in the
doctors and nurses are moving in but
anything like that coming from the top
down is gonna have pushback and it's
hard to implement right they can't just
make a new office building you know few
weeks so finding like this is a solution
have a register of empty properties that
there are any given moment right that
could you need to use or stuff like that
so yeah yeah yeah I mean it's a again
valid point you're making right but
there but there are always lots and lots
of empty properties about if you know
where they are then they can be yeah
yeah yeah I take a added complication
with this particular disease though is
that we don't even have you know at some
point somebody has it they survive and
now what do we do with them because we
don't have proper data on whether they
actually have immunity or not at this
point on so that adds that throws a
wrench in in all kinds of stuff no part
of resiliency I think going forward is
to be able to collect the kind of data
that is needed for things like this but
on the other hand it has to be data that
people trust you know um because the
top-down doesn't work you know the
bottom-up isn't working because we don't
have the data to implement things from
the bottom-up and we don't have trust
you know so I think part of resiliency I
mean all this stuff is connected part of
resiliency though we we have to talk
about trust we have to talk about data
we have to talk about all of these
things for it to actually be resilient
yeah and that is something we could
potentially do with 10,000 people and
$100,000 is design a cope at 19
information source that the 10,000
trusted and if the 10,000 it's designed
for the 10,000 to trust it and to see
transparently how that was created and
how the trans entrusted and how we
listened to them and how then it can be
extrapolated that more more and more
people would trust it but anyone coming
up with that how's the trust problems
has the data problems like you need it
from the ground up because we don't
trust top-down anymore the government
sites even more like are you lying are
we in here so you can install 5g what's
coming like I don't think our
governments are in cahoots I did not
give them that much capacity they're
doing them yeah I don't give a classy
but yeah I don't trust them either yeah
in in this game a world you know we have
you know the institutions on you know
there's there's just all these nasty
incentives that are incentivizing people
to act in ways and there's the whole
concept you know of there's there's not
a balance of understanding that I'm an
individual I'm also part of the group
I'm my individuality actually depends on
the group otherwise without the group
I'm not an individual you know there's
there's not a sense of this kind of
thing so right now as we talked about
before we don't live in game B or
anything like it we live in game a so
you know how do we how do we take what
we have and and transition this forward
I think this is the hardest problem
across all domains you know how do we
how do we bootstrapped within game as
far as Trust goes as far as you see and
those are the but that's why I'm having
this solution raisings is to showcase
what we could do with 10,000 people
hundred thousand dollars and then
literally get 10,000 people and vote on
or like just do any project and then
continually make it better because any
of them would make life much closer to
game B than it currently is especially
if we all know it operates them together
and they're done so with transparency
and democracy or better but we're at the
hour would anyone like to give their
closing statements and then I will
discuss what we're doing for the next
two weeks at this time on Wednesday I
think
Edwards
in the last thing he was saying that
it's all connected and so you can't even
talk about building resilience in
without also having a conversation about
things like transparency and Trust is
absolutely right because without that
you can't build the resilience it
doesn't it doesn't actually mean
anything
so yeah it's sir it's a big big big big
problem how to get from here to there
it's yeah yeah for me personally all I'm
doing is trying to build as much
resilience into my own personal life as
I can because I feel like that that's
where my sovereignty ends is around my
own life it's not even part of not even
a teeny weeny weeny part of the
conversation on the legacy media you
know this this idea about how vulnerable
we were to any kind of calamity that was
coming down the road at us right there
there is not even the beginnings of this
conversation and so I am less than
hopeful that any meaningful lessons are
going to be learned from this I mean
David Jubilee was there I think David
sweat Lowe made the point that you know
we could not ask for a kinder gentler
global catastrophe to offer us a chance
to learn some lessons and wake up and do
things better right and and if we fail
to learn the lessons from this one and
the next one may very well not be so
gentle so yeah it worries me that
although they're confident of
conversations like this one going on
right meaningful useful constructive
conversations talking about the right
kinds of things but it doesn't seem to
be bubbling up into the you know the
stuff that the majority of people still
sit down and watch for an hour every
evening why I don't get it I'm
bewildered by the fact but especially
now pretty much everyone sitting down to
watch the nightly news right and get the
latest numbers of deaths from around the
world you know what I mean it's all
reduced down to numbers of infected
numbers of death curves and flattening
and blah-blah-blah-blah-blah
it's the same repeal every
single night just with different numbers
plugged into it you know I mean it's
really what what what are we talking
about what questions are we asking what
are we learning where are we going what
you know there's just this this is
unspoken assumption that in a
weaks everything's gonna go back to
normal it will be just display it was
before and if that is what ends up
happening I can't we've failed on a
grand scale that's all our Juice
if we need everyone to do it then we've
already failed but if we need 10,000
people to come together and create
something because it's really hard to be
awake in this world it's really hard to
know this was coming down the pipeline
now that it is those of us who already
knew or were like thank God everyone
understands no they're not because they
might go back together and create
something good enough you can't if it's
just ten thousand my community we're
making our own food in our own solar
panels and this is because another
people come and steal it from you but
ten thousand people absolutely can
create a food app ten thousand people
can create a system of mapping our
supply chain can create a system of
holding our politicians accountable can
create a system of how new we trust this
information for any particular subject
and and created from that the base is
just about having a process in a system
and that's what I'm looking to do with
these and also looking for the people
who want to continually have these
conversations on the meadow issue and so
this week we're talking about resiliency
efficiency and fragility next week on
Wednesday we're talking about packaging
and like raw resources how do we know
our about raw resources packaging
materials how do we what do we do for
solutions in in that realm and then we
have that it with the week after we are
talking about the meta connectedness how
do we solve things in one area when it
reverberates into every other area and
how did how do you deal with with the
interconnectedness of it and I'm
thinking in the week after that although
I don't know the date of it we're gonna
talk about trust
cuz Trust is a big issue and it's
something that is eroding and we're all
paying the price the people don't trust
our median government's is costing all
of us right now and I am no way to trust
our media and governments and I still
think they're the best we have at this
moment and so we have to trust them a
little bit and listen so that we can
work together at a grand scale well
we're building new things and new
resiliency and not letting them take
over our lives
I'm already six minutes past but ever
did you have anything else you'd like
that yeah I'll just kind of combine with
both of you said in kind of a simple
metaphor and that is
imagine an alcoholic that drinks and
drinks and they're taken to the ER with
you know alcohol poisoning and the ER
goes through all these heroic you know
medical technology things to get them
okay again you know that's the
flattening of the curve and everything
but then they're just thrown back out on
the street and the actual the actual
problem has not even been address you
know that the immediate trauma has been
solved but the problem has not been
addressed and they're gonna be back
again for the same thing and I think
about well the solution to alcoholism if
you can do it is one day at a time you
know just one day at a time so if you
think of the ten thousand people and the
hundred thousand dollars as a day and
just one day at a time I don't know of
any other way of doing that except you
know just this one day at a time has to
start happening yeah like I said I would
love to have people who particularly
want to work through how do we create a
process that we could include ten
thousand people in to come up with a
solution that they want to be a part of
to come up with with basically any of
the ideas would come from any solution
raising so anyone who wants to do that
I'm looking to meet weekly for an hour
and move it forward and basically work
through all of the processes and
questions during that so I'm gonna say
goodbye to YouTube periscope and I will
probably see you tomorrow if I'm not
grocery shopping the plan is to a
grocery shopping but we'll see